

SCM ERP Product Developer seeking assignment in Full Stack Development, Software Development, Application Programming, Angular, JavaScript, Spring MVC, HTML, CSS, LESS, MySQL, NoSQL, REST APIs, GIT, Maven



Current Designation: SCM ERP Product Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Current Company: IVTL Infoview Technologies Private Ltd Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Current Location: Namakkal

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Coimbatore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: SCM ERP Product Developer, Software Developer, Full Stack Development, Software Development, Application

Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Gap Analysis, Angular, Java Script, Spring

MVC,HTML,CSS,LESS,MySQL,NoSQL,REST APIs,GIT,Maven,Jenkins

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

### Summary

SCM ERP Product Developer with 4+ years of work exposure in Full Stack Development, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Gap Analysis, Angular, JavaScript, Spring MVC, HTML, CSS, LESS, MySQL, NoSQL, REST APIs, GIT, Maven, Jenkins.

# Work Experience

# IVTL Infoview Technologies Private Ltd as SCM ERP Product Developer Jun 2016 to Till Date

(2018 - 2020) - SCM ERP Product ( Developer)

Worked as a developer in ERP Product under Procurement and Cost sub-systems.

In Procurement Management application, it covers all processes related to the planning and buying of goods and services.

In Cost Management application, it includes activities such as planning, estimating, budgeting, financing, funding etc.

Responsible for UI design, creating various user and data validations and implementing server side logics in Java 8

Used RESTApi to obtain data from server and generate operations on those data in all possible formats, such as XML and JSON.

Verified code standards with SonarQube and related tools.

(2017 - 2018) Data Migration Project (Developer)

Developed an interface application which is used to transfer bulk data from one database to another.

The main focus of this application is to reduce the data transferring complexity with the help of Multi-threading and batch process.

This application has been designed using Spring, HTML5 and Less. Written Business validation based on customer use in java8.

(2016 - 2017) HUE-AC-CONVERSION Project (Developer)

This application is mainly for the business enterprise sector where n number of customers can access this application with high security policy.

Main role is to convert Pascal language into Java for creating bug free web application with same

business logic.

Analysed and converted complex Pascal code logics and created appropriate testcases to cover all the use cases.

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from INSTITUTE OF ROAD AND TRANSPORT TECHNOLOGY, ERODE in 2016

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Angular, JavaScript, Java8, Spring MVC	
HTML, CSS/LESS	
Mysql, Nosql (Cassandra)	
REST APIs, OOP	
GIT, Maven, Jenkins	

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

#### **Affirmative Action**

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

**Work Authorization**